# Killian Jochen McShane

# Computer Science Student



Final-year student of computer science at The University of Liverpool, specialising in artificial intelligence and data science. Proficient in Python, R, Java, SQL, and functional Haskell programming languages with experience using software development and data analysis tools such as Apache Ant, Power BI and Tableau. I am highly IT and Mathematically literate, with a strong background in customer-facing roles.

## **Education**

#### BSc (Hons) Computer Science with Artificial Intelligence The University of Liverpool

09/2018 - Present

First Class (Expected)

### Career

#### **Data Analyst**

The Walton Centre NHS Trust

10/2021 - Present

Liverpool

- Developing predictive modelling, clinical and patient flow algorithms for statistical data analysis.
- Providing actionable insight to recommend opportunities and improvements through analytics with SQL & Power BI.

## **Customer Service Representative**

The Royal Bank of Scotland

10/2017 - 03/2018

Belfast

- Teamwork, exceeding KPI expectations and preventing escalations was key in this high-pressure environment.
- Asked pertinent questions to empathetically deliver aid and successfully resolve issues quickly.

#### **Customer Service Representative**

Teleperformance UK

10/2016 - 04/2017

Newry

- Handled and managed customer complaints.
- Clarified payment options and credit management.

#### **Data Analysis Spring Internship**

FM Environmental

04/2015

Newry

- Analysed and processed friction and fluid calculations.
- Relayed insights from data analysis with Excel to aid engineers in their decision making.

## Languages

• English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

German

Professional Working Proficiency

### **Skills**



## **Achievements**

Founder & President of The Data Science and Artificial Intelligence Society at The University of Liverpool

I manage the society. My leadership involves chairing meetings, attracting funding, and managing relationships with stakeholders.

University of Liverpool Leadership Programme (2021)

Attended the university's leadership programme to boost my leadership potential and develop my professional skills.

BT Young Scientist Boot Camp (2015)

Selected for and won the competition. Lead a team of 5 individuals through the development lifecycle of a new product.

#### **Interests**

Boxing	Running		Mathematics		
Deep Learning		Big Data		Crypto & Blockchain	

## **Projects**

Dissertation Project: A.I. for Political Sentiment Classification (Python, Google Colab)

Using Google's BERT natural language processing machine learning model and various social media APIs, I plan to web-scrape a dataset of political comments and classify them by their political leaning.

Automated Build Deployment & Testing (Java)

Build deployment using Apache Ant, Java, XML build file, and JUnit.

Short-term Stock Price Prediction Web-app (Python, JS) Stock price prediction using an LSTM Neural Network, Twitter's API and natural language processing, sentiment analysis of Tweets.